What we are in the midst of right now is
the United States massively losing to
China. China has built an industrialized
version of clinical trial infrastructure
for first- inhuman trials that is so
efficient and massively quick that
they're just able to go faster and
cheaper into the thing that matters
most, which is first in human trials.
What started as a place for American
companies to come run clinical trials to
get data and then take it to the FDA and
then do larger trials in the United
States has now created a flywheel
structure within China where now just
Chinese companies run their clinical
trials faster than the American
companies and then bring their Chinese
discovered drugs to the United States.
And what happens is the capital flow the
risk capital then says ah these
companies are more efficient I will fund
these sorts of aspects.
>> What does Strand do? So, Strand designs
what we call next generation genetic
medicines. You have DNA inside of your
cells. The DNA makes RNA copies of
itself and then that RNA makes proteins.
And actually, life is all proteins,
right? Your skin, your hair, your
organs, every cell is basically just
proteins stacked together. That is
everything that we are, right? You don't
really see the DNA and the RNA. It's
very small. The protein is what we think
of as like our being. And so the way to
actually intervene in disease, the way
to get to its core is to create the
correct proteins. Right? If if you have
a deficiency, everything from an enzyme
problem to a rare disease to cystic
fibrosis, it's usually a problem with a
protein that is being incorrectly made
by a cell. And so what we have figured
out over decades and decades is what's
gone wrong with that protein and what
would need to go right to fix that
protein or how you would replace that
protein correctly. What we have not
figured out is how to make the cells do
that. And that's because it's this very
complicated problem to tell certain
cells in the body to to do various
different things.
>> And so what we are really focused on
building,
>> we know what proteins need to be made.
we know where they need to be made. What
we need to do is get the message of what
type of protein to the place in your
body where they need to be made and we
need to do that effectively and safely.
And so what we have essentially figured
out a way to do is take that message
which is in the form of an a molecule
called RNA. A lot of people are familiar
with it from the co vaccines but those
are very small examples of what RNA
could actually be utilized to do. And
then we have found a way to send those
messages into the body into diseased
areas where they can access the cells
and essentially return the cells to a
state of homeostasis which either
corrects the problem or in the case of
cancer removes the problem any of those
pieces. And so that's the base case of
what we're trying to accomplish.
>> Mhm. So let me back up and give people a
little bit of context. So the first time
we met was in Boston at a dinner. Yeah.
Do you want to describe I don't think
they'll mind who else was there? Who
else was at the dinner?
>> Another biotech CEO, Phil Strandwitz,
and a
>> I don't know how to classify Jaime's
job. He's a leading professor at the MIT
>> bit of a polymath
>> polymath MIT media lab professor,
healthcare entrepreneur, advisor to
anyone who wants to know fancy things
sort of guy. And then me.
>> Yeah. Right. and you [laughter] I'm
already an investor in Whole Biome,
Phil's company. Love what Jaime's up to
and very interested in what he's
building as well. We can put that in the
show notes. We'll put all that in the
show notes. And then we met and part of
the reason I became very interested in
Strand. There were a lot of reasons. So,
one is the technology, the results, the
photograph or I should say images that
you showed me, which we'll get to in a
second. The second is founder builder
who is technical but for whom also this
company this is going to be a strongly
worded statement but is like
existential.
>> Yeah.
>> You're not a hired gun CEO who has been
brought in. This is very much entwined
with your identity and personal mission
which I find very attractive [laughter]
and quite interrelated with that is the
fact that I found you to be a very good
communicator over that dinner. Right. I
learned a lot. You recommended a number
of books to me at the dinner and then
afterwards.
I'd say chief among which was the the
Janentech
>> fantastic book
>> origin story which is one of the best I
would say business books I've ever read
just unbelievably good because it it
also and I can't believe it made it past
all the Genentech sensors but like
[laughter]
actual contracts I mean screenshots of
contracts negotiations mistakes
all of the
serendipitous lucky moments and unforced
errors by universities and so on that
had to coales for Genentech to even
survive survive. It's just an incredible
story. And
I
also, just again, this is more for
people listening than for you, but I'll
continue to fluff a little longer, which
is
>> also that you seem to me to be very
aggressive without being haphazard.
Right. So you you were just furious at
this dinner when I started trying to get
an idea of the general biotech scene in
Boston and asking questions about
various startups and figures and
companies at how conservative and
dogmatic maybe would be a very generous
way to put it. You view a lot of folks,
not all but the default, right? The
status quo. And in contrast, you're
taking big swings, right? like you were
taking big swings. So all of those
things were attractive. When it comes to
strand, let's talk about the image for a
second. What was the image that you
showed me or images?
>> I happened to show you a photo of one of
our patients, one of the very first
patients that entered our trial. The way
that these early stage trials work in
oncology with a patient with stage 4
melanoma. In early stage trials, you end
up with patients who have been through
every exhausted every option by the time
they end up in your trial and they often
have pretty progressed disease. And so
>> you hope you can offer something to
these patients. They had melanoma. So
that's a skin cancer. But they had not
only aggressive what we call cutaneous
metastasis, which is across their
surface of their body in the skin, but
they had what's called visceral
metastasis, which that's actually what
kills you in melanoma is the metastasis
to the organs of your body. And it was
in their lungs. It was in other sorts of
areas. I think muscle deposits and bone
deposits. And in addition to that, this
patient had had multiple other therapies
that historically actually melanoma
responds very well to. What's
unfortunate about the current state of
affairs in melanoma and in some cancers
is we have these imunotherapy drugs.
What the biggest blockbuster of the last
few years is a drug called Kitruda from
Merc. Incredible miracle drug. Won a
Nobel Prize a few years ago. In
melanoma, if you respond to that drug, a
lot of patients do, that's great. If you
don't, the likelihood of survival begins
to diminish very quickly. And this
patient had had [clears throat] kitruda.
They had had a whole number of other
drugs through many what they call lines
of therapy. You get a drug,
>> your cancer responds or it doesn't. you
you know if it doesn't respond you go to
the next and the doctor the oncologist
cycles you through a number of drugs and
this patient was at a fairly advanced
hospital that not only had given them
the what they call the standard of care
and then the second line standard of
care they had given them actually a
number of other just like maybe this
will work maybe this will work you know
trying to help the patient stay alive
and the picture that we have and this is
in you know someone if you Google our
Asco poster which is a Clinical Oncology
Conference.
>> How do you spell ASCO?
>> ASCO. It's an abbreviation for the
American Society of Clinical Oncology.
It's a meeting every summer in Chicago
that sort of is the big breakthroughs in
clinical medicine for oncology. It's the
top of the top in a lot of ways for
people, you know, big results, small
results. We had presented this photo
there and I had met you a little bit
afterwards to show I mean the the photo
itself is quite striking and it's in
that poster.
>> It's basically a body riddled with
cancers. I mean they're everywhere.
>> I like to say you don't have to be an
oncologist to look at that scan and
understand the extent of which this
patient responded. Just riddled and then
no more. And one of the things as a
scientist Tim you mentioned something
earlier which was that this is more than
a company for me and actually a company
is only about one third to one half of
the time that I've spent on this like
mission to make genetic medicine work
correctly for patients.
>> One of the greatest accomplishments in
that, you know, career that I've had
thus far is being able to like say that
you did help a person. If that was just
one person, one patient, I'd say, "Wow,
what a career." We dream of more. We
have big ambitions here at Strand. I
have ambitions for how many people in
the scale at which we're going to be
able to help people. However, like that
was the first time that I really felt
like our science went out into the world
and it took, you know, someone's
grandmother and not only kept them
alive, but we're a year and a half in
and they still have no detectable like
lesions.
>> Yeah. It's wild. in the investor deck,
right? The pitch deck that I initially
read and had I apologize for that, but
like a million and 500,000
questions about for the non-technical
folks, right? The muggles, they can look
things up and are curious. What are
things that stuck for them like
particular slides or phrases? [snorts]
certainly the images, but is there
anything else that comes to mind that
really resonated with people from that
deck?
>> There's one other bigger, you know,
generalist investor who who had come
into the round personally. And I had I'd
been having a conversation with them
about something in oncology that we call
the Kaplan Meyer curve.
>> Kaplan Meyer curve, if you're looking at
oncology results, is sort of a survival
graph.
>> Yeah. So, you know, you maybe look at
like two years and you look at from 100%
where you start the study and then it
looks like a step ladder going down. The
standard of care line has some amount of
people like steps down and you want to
have your drug be significantly above
that. either having more people alive
longer or you know you have like a what
they call the long tail where like
everything goes to zero in standard of
care at a certain time point but you
have an amount of patients that just
like look cured they continue on for
many years.
>> Mhm.
>> And in drug development we get very used
to looking at those graphs and sort of
making very statistical calls and saying
oh this doesn't look like it's active or
this drug's it or isn't that great. But
I think one of the things that I've
spoken to some generalists, some of our
larger investors who maybe aren't from
the biotech world, and I've I've tried
to zero in on some of those survival
graphs with is to say, you know, when we
look at these steps, these are lives,
the lines that go down on this, the
vertical part of the step is someone's
loved one dying. But the ones that go
horizontal and every time you see
something go further along that is
someone who got to exper even if it's
just three months you have no idea what
that means within that person's life.
And
when we take that that Kaplan Meyer
curve and those steps and we zero in on
each patient, we start to look at them
and we start to say like this is a
patient that didn't think they would see
Christmas in 2024 and they just
celebrated the new year of 2026.
[clears throat]
>> That I think is meaningful in what we're
doing now. Whether or not that will be a
good product, right? There's a
difference between a good drug and a
good product. I'd say the good drug is
can someone take this and it does
something like injecting a therapy into
someone in a way that is very hard to
replicate but did a great thing for that
individual person is a good drug
fundamentally. It is a good drug. It
helped that person, right? Mhm.
>> And a good product is much more this is
where the idea of how we get medicines
to people come into come into play. I'll
give you a different example. There's
something else that we're working on
called invivo cell therapy. Essentially,
there's an entire type of science that
we have discovered how to take the
immune cells out of a patient, take
their immune cells out, reprogram them
so that they learn how to attack
cancerous blood cells and then put them
back into a patient.
>> Mhm.
>> They are phenomenal drugs. There are
people who are about to die of like
myoma and then they get this drug. But
the drug costs, not making money, the
drug costs $750,000 to make just to
manufacture. It costs three months of
time to manufacture.
It's very hard to see a world in which
that drug has a large impact on the
patient population because of the the
fundamental cost, the cogs, the cost of
goods sold,
>> not biotech, just straight business. The
cost of doing it and the time it takes
to get it to people, that's a bad
product. Y
>> and so if you could say instead of
taking the cells out of the body, if you
could reprogram them while they're still
in the patient, now you have a good
product because you know if you can make
the cells recognize the cancer, the
immune cells program to activate against
the cancer in the same way, but make it
an outpatient procedure where a patient
just gets hooked up to an IV bag for 2
hours and then goes home.
>> Mhm.
>> That is a phenomenal product. I have to
look at this from the perspective of a
non specialist because that's what I am.
Yes.
>> But like if you were giving a TED talk
on this and had to kind of get across
>> at least part of what you're doing, I
feel like what you just said sort of
hits the nail on the head. Yeah. Right.
Within the first few minutes, you'd have
to talk about the central dogma, so to
speak, of like DNA as master copy, so to
speak, mRNA, and then protein. But just
like in brief, could you describe
the treatment, what the treatment
actually looked like for the patient in
those photographs, the before and after?
Like dots everywhere representing tumors
and then holy [__] right? I think
everyone, whether they're technical or
not, that looks at that deck probably
had the same response, right, to those
images.
>> So in cancer, you have you have
chemotherapy, I think people are fairly
familiar with. You also have
amunotherapy [clears throat]
which is the ability to activate the
immune system to attack the cancer
directly and that's what some of the
biggest blockbuster drugs of all time
are currently Merks Kitruda Bristol
Meyer Squibs Updo and then there's a
number of other types of amunotherapies
which are classified as checkpoint
blockades. Mhm.
>> So what that is is your cells
essentially have a way to tell the
immune system that they are your cells.
>> Mhm.
>> So you don't want your immune system to
attack your own body obviously. And so
one of the mechanisms that you have is
this IMU signal that your cells can send
to the immune system. Cancers hijack
that mechanism to protect themselves
from being attacked by the immune
system. And what we figured out was a
way to block those signals. And that's
the entire field of amunotherapy. Not
the entire field, but I would say a vast
majority of the field of amunotherapy
and the successes of the last decade of
treating cancer and also commercial
success for a lot of these companies has
been based on further refining better
checkpoints.
The problem with that is that they're
all very similar mechanistically. And so
if one doesn't work, if you have cancer
and I give you kituda and it doesn't
work, the chances that the next types of
therapies will work since all of them
are very similar mechanistically.
the chances diminish quite drastically
and there's some nuance here and I'm
sure if there's you know oncologists
listening to me they're like no but you
don't know in double negative this
cancer if you combine with these it
doesn't matter right in general these
mechanisms become degenerative and we
don't have good additional options to
excite the immune system
>> a second theory for going back to the
'9s was if instead of just you know sort
of
blocking the cancer's ability to hide
from the immune system. If that's not
enough, what we actually need to do is
we need to activate the immune system
directly. And it would be best if you
could send that activation signal from
the tumor itself. So now you have a
tumor instead of just blocking the
tumor's ability to hide. You actually
have a tumor that's sort of screaming
like, I am a foreign object. Please come
and eat me.
>> That's kind of how immune systems kill
things. like like eat the other cells.
>> Yep.
>> And so the issue, this is not new. This
is basic science from like immunology
from the '90s. The problem is we haven't
had a good way to get the tumors to send
those signals. We've tried to make the
signals in the lab and then inject them
into the tumors. And the problem is the
signal just like goes away immediately
and then it's circulating in the body
and the immune system doesn't know
what's sending the signal. We've tried
everything we can to like make this
signal artificial and get it into the
tumors. And every single time we do it,
it's either not enough in terms of no
efficacy or it activates the immune
system in all sorts of places we don't
want it and it causes all sorts of
toxicities. And so what we are doing
with our medicine is
delivering the instructions into the
cancer cells
>> in a way that causes the cancer to
basically send its own signal out. So
it's artificial in that we have made it
in a lab, but instead of making the
signal, we're making a message that
tricks the cancer into sending the
signal. And so that is drastically
different. It makes a huge difference in
both safety and efficacy because now you
are recapitulating
how the signal works naturally.
>> If the cancers weren't cancerous, if
they were just deregulated and you know
cells were starting to grow out of
control, your cell would naturally send
the signal and be like, "Oh no,
something's wrong." And your body would
take care of it. You actually generate
cancer like all the time in your body in
terms of disregulated cells. your immune
system just comes in and takes care of
it before it becomes like a, [snorts]
you know, when it becomes a real
problem. That's when you get tumors.
That's when you get the disease we call
cancer.
>> And so what we're doing is we're sort of
resetting that system. We're having the
tumors resend the signal out. And so
what we created in that first drug was a
very simple administration procedure.
You take our genetic medicine and you
inject it into the tumor directly. And
what that does is the immune system
comes into the tumor and it kills it.
But then it gets activated by that
killing process and it learns what the
tumors look like and it can better
identify the other tumors that have been
hiding throughout the body.
>> So that's the point that I was hoping to
get to. It's basically like in this in
the case of this patient, not to belabor
this point, but it's like you injected,
if I'm remembering correctly, into
cutaneous, meaning like at the just
under the skin.
Not sure what the right term is.
Nodules, like instances of cancer. Yeah.
Right. So, my follow-up question was
going to be like, well, then how do you
suddenly get to the visceral instances?
Right.
>> Yeah.
>> And I think that's what you're
describing. And within the world of
oncology, is that a novel observation?
Is that something that is new in terms
of being able to do that? It's something
called the abscopal response or the
abscopal effect which means that one
tumor is sort of what you've put the
activating drug into and that's where
the immune system will attack first but
now the immune system is activated and
educated to go and kill the other
tumors. It's not new in the fact that
like I didn't come up with that name.
>> Yeah. It has been observed in limited
other settings
of a few other drugs that people have
have gone out with. I guess the problem
has been that it's been very very
limited in terms of the abscopal
response that other people have seen. So
>> for instance, you would have a patient
with a tumor maybe melanoma patient. So
they'd have a a cutaneous lesion, a skin
lesion on their chest, and then they'd
have another one on their shoulder, and
you would inject the one on the chest,
and the shoulder one would also kind of
shrink. They're [clears throat] in the
same region, right? The immune system is
sort of like fighting the cancer in the
same region, but you wouldn't
necessarily see that happen in like the
lungs. And so one of the big push backs
on a drug like the one that we took to
the clinic two years ago was,
you know, you don't die from having
tumors all over your skin. You die from
when they metastasize into your lungs
and into your liver and, you know,
impact the organ functioning. That's how
patients die of melanoma.
So if you are only able to address the
tumors that you can either inject or
that are near the injected tumors, you
you won't have an effective drug if if a
patient already is like further along.
>> Mhm.
>> We are to my knowledge one of the first
companies, if not the first company to
demonstrate a direct injectable drug
into the tumor
that in a large number of patients,
>> this isn't a one-off. There wasn't one
miracle patient that had that. That is a
beautiful photo of that patient. I'm so
happy that they're still on the trial
and still doing great and it's amazing.
But, you know, this is about being
broadly applicable because that's how
you actually impact population level
lives.
>> And so, we are the first company that
I'm aware of to show this sort of like
extent of abscopal response in visceral
deep organ metastases in a you multitude
of patients. And really right off the
bat, I mean this is from the very first
patients we put on this trial at the
very beginning of it
>> began responding.
>> Yeah,
>> that is very uncommon. It's very
uncommon to have patients on a phase one
trial on the drug 6 months later. And of
our first three patients that ever
entered this trial in the summer of
2024, two of those three are still on
the trial 18 months later. M
>> that is something that I think is fairly
shocking.
>> Yeah.
>> And if we were a traditional biotech
company, we'd be really happy with all
of this data and we'd say, "Wow, let's
take this forward." However, you I think
the real message of Strand and what we
can accomplish in genetic medicine is we
don't have to stop it just injecting
into the tumors. There are a number of
concerns with injecting tumors from a
product perspective, not a drug
perspective, but a product perspective.
Right? The difference between, you know,
a drug is all about does this work and a
product is about how will these patients
get these drugs and injecting directly
into a tumor is doable and most
oncologists can handle it, especially
for skin cancer patients. But as you go
to rural health communities, it gets
harder and harder to have doctors that
have that training. And as you get to
other sorts of tumors beyond skin cancer
patients, some of their skin lesions
have been removed by a surgeon. And then
you go beyond skin cancer. How are you
going to inject a patient with nonswall
cell lung cancer? Like you start to get
this idea of there's a limited amount of
patients you can access, right? And so
you have a product may be limitation
>> in cancer. The way that we actually
treat cancer patients is that there's an
infusion clinic. You go to the infusion
clinic. the oncologists and the nurse
practitioners and everyone technicians
hook you up to some sort of an infusion
and then the oncologist can monitor
multiple patients at a time. And that's
what our infrastructure looks like right
now of how we treat patients. And if you
want to have the largest impact in
medicine, you need to make medicines
that plug into existing infrastructure.
As much as you want to like tell
everyone, hey, change everything about
how you think about treating patients,
the way to like have a near-term impact
is to build drug solutions that can plug
into existing infrastructures. You know,
if we become a giant biotechnology
company that has all sorts of resources,
maybe we can talk about changing how
everyone gives drugs, but for right now,
if we want to be able to help the most
amount of patients in the near term, we
need to plug into that infrastructure.
We need to find ways that we can access
organs. I'd say in addition the
bloodstream is also a really good way to
get around the body believe it or not
like I mean the bloodstream carries
oxygen to everywhere in your body and so
if your drugs can travel through the
bloodstream and get where they're going
very effective
in genetic medicine I would call it the
holy grail for the last 30 years has
been thinking about how do we IV
administer intravenous which means into
the bloodstream
>> administer
genetic medicines that can get to places
throughout the body. We've been trapped
in one organ for the past 30 years and
that's the liver. The liver naturally
filters your blood and thus it picks up
a lot of these genetic medicines that we
put into the bloodstream. Y
>> and so what we've done for the last 30
years is figure out how we can treat
diseases in the liver with this like
it's this old internet meme which is
like step one blank step two question
mark step three profit right I remember
like the old days of Reddit people used
to use that structure right step one do
this step two question mark step three
profit in biotech in genetic medicine
the joke is like step one prove it works
in the liver step two question mark step
three we'll treat all these diseases and
after 30 years we've really nailed step
one.
>> Mhm.
>> And step two has remained this like big
question mark. And so when we started
Strand, our number one goal actually was
not even to get to this first drug. As
amazing as it's been for these patients
and as happy as I am that we have been
able to help those people in their lives
and as impressive as it is, our main
goal was to solve this step two question
mark that's been sitting there in plain
sight. Mhm.
>> And I guess the big piece here is that
like, you know, everyone who thinks they
know what they're talking about in
genetic medicine will say, "Well, the
issue is delivery." And it's like, "You
need to be able to deliver." And I'm
like,
>> "That's a very handwavy."
>> Again, it's just a cheap answer, which
is like not wrong, but it is incomplete.
And I believe that it's actually three
problems at once. It's three children in
their father's trench coat pretending to
be an adult. It's like we're delivery.
And then you open it up and it's like
potency, specificity, and delivery are
all here inside. And no one wants to
hear that because people want simple
solution. They want like, oh, it's
delivery, so we'll just fix delivery.
And I mean, just 30 years in, no one has
a good idea about this piece. And I I'd
say that the thing at Strand when I
started the company that I just could
not understand why everyone didn't see
what I was trying to tell them and I was
very bad at pitching. You think I'm too
much of a scientist now perhaps or maybe
your audience does if they're listening
but like man you should have seen my
very technical zero market insight pitch
deck of 2018. That is complete dog [__]
It is an awful [laughter] I am can't
believe someone funded us. I'm a huge
fan of Elon Musk's like first principles
based thinking, right? I don't know if
Elon is the one who invented first
principles based thinking, but I think
he's probably the main evangelist and
popularizer of this like thinking
modality where, you know, if you take
SpaceX for example, his idea was what is
the thing preventing commercial space
flight? And it's dollars per kilogram,
right, of launch. Like it's just like
dollars per kilogram. That's it. Like
how do you get it down? And you start to
like, well, where's the cost centers in
a launch? And you go, okay, well, the
cost center in a launch is in like these
rockets,
>> trashing rockets,
>> these fuselages that were just trashing
80% of it. And you go, well, like, why
don't we just like reuse them? And
people are like, well, you know, they do
this, they do that. You know, they're
hard to retrieve. They're in the ocean,
they're floating, they can't. And he
goes, he goes, "What if they like land
themselves?" And it's like, that's an
insane person thing to say. What I want
the world to understand is that we are
standing right now on the precipice of a
revolution in genetic medicine. And
that's important for a number of
reasons. One, it's important because
there are near-term diseases that we're
going to be able to solve. We're going
to be able to get to a point in the not
too distant future where I think a lot
of types of cancers are at the very
least chronic diseases instead of death
sentences. You know, we all want to get
to cures. I want to get to cures, but we
are getting at least to a point where
it's a manageable disease, right? That's
I think a near-term
piece,
>> right?
>> There's sort of multiple lines of
technology that are coming together that
I think people are not fully
appreciating what what they're going to
mean for the future of medicine. And so
there's a lot of focus right now on AI
based drug discovery and people are
building proteins and antibodies and all
sorts of stuff with AI models that are
doing incredible things. We have decades
of work on designing exquisite proteins
that do all sorts of stuff from edit
genomes to cure whatever in some sort of
mouse model. What we don't have is the
infrastructure,
the medical biio medicine infrastructure
that gets any of these things, these
discoveries, whether they're made by a
human with Microsoft Word stitching
amino acids together, whether they're
made by an LLM that knows exactly all
the pieces that are going to make this,
whether it's made by high throughput
screen of 14 different robots in
concert, it doesn't matter. What matters
is how we're going to get those into
patients, how we're going to get them
into the places they need. And I think
about this as this infrastructure of
medicine comes forward and what this
will actually mean for the future of
healthcare. Anyone in any sort of a
place of power throughout the world I
think needs to understand where where in
the next 10 to 20 years we very well may
be headed with medicine which is smaller
indications, niche indications. We are
moving in a way where I think medicine
becomes maybe not completely bespoke but
much more refined. And the way that we
get there, we're going to get there
technologically and we're going to get
there from a design perspective much
quicker than we're going to have the
infrastructure to actually deliver those
medicines to people safely, effectively
at scale. And so our goal at Strand and
our challenge is building drugs today
that impact patients lives.
>> Yep.
>> We're not a research institute. Our goal
is not to do really cool research on
mice and join the ranks of people who
have cured mice of cancer. There's
millions of them. There could be a Nobel
Prize every five minutes for someone
who's cured a mouse of cancer. Our goal
is to cure human beings of human being
cancer. [snorts] Our goal is to cure
human beings of human being diseases and
do so in a safe, effective, scalable way
that impacts a person's life as little
as possible.
>> And that is what we're building as a
commercial organization. We're building
drugs today, but what we're doing is
we're laying the groundwork for this
infrastructure to where when we're
successful in tumors with the new trial
that we're running this year, when we're
successful with being able to IV
deliver, you know, infuse a genetic
medicine that goes to the tumors, we
have an instruction manual, what we call
a payload, right? The protein that we're
tricking the cancer into making. We have
one that we've chosen. But success there
actually means that I could now in 6
weeks design a completely new protein to
be delivered to the tumors and I could
just go over and over and over again.
I'm only going to be gated by the
infrastructure I have to build like new
ones of those and the FDA's ability to
move quickly with us as we try to test
new and newer things. But we know the
general high level safety of this
>> that's coming right that's coming in a
lot of other areas of the body. We're
we're designing things to get into TE-C
cells so we can help, you know,
temporarily
influence the immune system so you could
take out things like autoimmune disease
and allow patients to revert back to
their pre-treated state without doing
any sort of genetic modification. We're
trying to get all sorts of these
therapies forward. And every time we
have a success, we lay the groundwork
for this infrastructure going forward. I
want people to understand it one because
we have large ambitions.
>> A lot of people have thought first they
thought that the first principalbased
approach we were taking was incorrect.
They're like it's a delivery problem.
You need to build a better delivery
vehicle. Why don't you focus on that?
And I'm like okay everyone's done that
right now. We've shown this complex
solution actually fixes this like
age-old problem and we're going to be
continuing to move that forward. I'd say
the biotechnology industry will be
dragged kicking and screaming into into
the future or it will, you know, be
built up in a new way from new players.
For us, I want to find the people
throughout the globe who want to partner
on these things. The innovators in
America and those are all sorts of
different sorts of folks. Those are
people in policy. Those are
>> Yeah.
>> You know, people.
>> So, let's dig into that just for a
second. Like for instance, with this
podcast, let's say I was like, "Well, I
got good news and I got bad news." The
bad news is
>> I can't put this out to my whole
audience. The good news is you get to
tell me which thousand people I send it
to and that gets handd delivered to a
thousand people, right? And I mean, a
similar way to look at it would be like,
"All right, you're giving a TED talk,
but it never gets shared online. It is
only for the thousand people in that
room, but you get to handpick them.
>> [snorts]
>> Who are those people? And it could just
be categories of person, but how would
you think about that? I think there are
people policy leaders not just in the
United States but you know across the
globe that need to think like critically
around
how we are going to both handle enable
and empower the future of medicine
because things you know incentives
things are going to look quite
differently 10 years from now than they
do today in terms of the scope and the
style in which we can build medicines
>> and the policy leaders are important.
Sorry to hop in, but because ultimately
they're going to determine the rules by
which healthcare is played. Is that one
way to put it?
>> Yeah. I mean, healthcare is very similar
to the space industry. Yeah.
>> In that policy leaders essentially have
two major pieces is that they are both
the arbiters of what is allowed to be
done and they are a major payer, not the
only payer, but they are a major payer
of the purchasing of that. And so as the
fundamentals of medical development
change,
>> yeah,
>> now I'm not making a drug that I hope to
give to, you know, 2 million people
worldwide.
>> I'm making a 100,000 variants of a drug
that I'm hoping to give to, you know,
10,000 people worldwide or 10,000
variants of a drug that I hope to give
to a 100,000 people worldwide. And I get
to more people, but there's more
variants. Both the regulatory and the
payment systems I think need to adapt
themselves to allow for that. It's on
us, the medical innovators and the
engineers and the entrepreneurs to build
systems that are still good products.
You have to think about where you're
going and then build a system that can
still be a good product. If it costs
10,000 times as much, it's not going to
work. Like it just won't work at scale
and you won't access these patients. But
if if you can see a path forward and
think creatively, I'm not a politics
guy, but I am fascinated by policy and
how incentives shape the future of
highly regulated industries like biio
medicine, like space, like all these
things. And and that is regulation plus
payment. I think that there's incredible
work to be done. And the last big time I
think productive collaboration between
worldwide policy makers and and the
United States as a leader. But the last
big collaboration of that came in the
80s when biotech started to take off in
the '9s when it really ripped right when
we started to harness the power of
recominant proteins. The Genzyme book
you plugged it earlier. That's
phenomenal.
>> Oh Janentech.
>> Janentech. Sorry. Jenzyme's the
Janentech of Boston. I get the two of
them were like
>> Yeah. But the Genentech book really, you
know, studying the history of Genzyme.
Jenzyme actually had the leader Henry
Tmir who was the actual quarterback I'd
say of the policy innovation, you know,
worked with government officials to
figure out like what will this new class
of medicines look like that aren't just
small molecules that you can take home.
Now we have antibodies. We have all
these drugs that are amazing because of
it. We have the Orphan and Rare Disease
Act which led to people building these
rare disease drugs. I'd say we need to
have more productive collaborative
conversations around what the future
will look like because things are going
to change very fast. You know, I read
the AI report from the the White House
for instance and sort of how the state
of AI is. And I read through it and I
was like, you actually need one of these
for biotechnology as well because things
are changing as rapidly
>> and it's going to be further accelerated
by AI and if we don't have some
productive conversations, we're going to
be stuck in one of two places. One is
where only the ultra rich can get the
really disruptive drugs because they're
the ones who can who can pay for it
because we don't have a system set up to
like have these new radical changes
commercial quick enough or or dispersed
quick enough. Or the second is the
inability to pay, the inability to find
ways that like support an ecosystem
makes an uninvestable thesis for
investors. And so all of these like
great innovations that we have coming
out of the lab right now just die on the
vine
>> get cut off at their knees because just
like space space industry it's a long
time cycle to read these things out and
you need capital to get there
>> so a lot of what I try to do in my own
meandering way is kind of answer the
like thousand people in a room question
>> interesting
>> and then to figure out it's like okay
let's just say you're spending time in
DC you sit down somebody their staffer
convince them to sit down for 30 minutes
right like what do you lead with right
then that can inform form potentially,
right? Like the website or appearances
on podcasts and stuff. So just in case
it's helpful, I can obviously share this
afterwards too, but it's like a couple
things come to mind, right? And I think
in terms of like, okay, what does the
TED So once you identify the people in
the room, then it's like what does the
TED talk look like if you got 20 minutes
on stage? And I mean, you're good at
this stuff, but sometimes you're so
close to it that it's helpful to have a
muggle.
>> No, I I want to hear this, Tim, by the
way. It's [laughter] a a free
communication lesson from someone much
more versed in the area.
>> Well, yeah, thank God because I can't do
science. So, [laughter]
got to allocate responsibilities. Well,
I don't want me in charge of developing
amunotherapy. So, the Christmas story
and the photos, right? So, if you kind
of like started with that, I'm just like
walking through in my my madeup TED
talk, right?
>> Yeah. And then let's just say you went
from there like okay let me take a
sidebar for a minute and you talked
about SpaceX right and the reusable
rockets right and the analogy also of
like once you have this engineering
platform developed from first principles
now you have something that is payload
agnostic right once you've made it
economically feasible and you have this
platform whether you're launching you
know superconductors into space as an
alternative to propellants for a
satellite reorientation. Check out
there's a company called Zeno. I might
have to redact this, but they're in New
Zealand CNN O. They're pretty [__]
amazing. But whether it's that, whether
it's something else is entirely up to
you in terms of deliverables because
you've done the hard work of developing
this engineering platform.
>> Yeah.
>> Then talking about like, okay, well,
what does that actually mean for
biotech? And you've got the holy grail,
right? How do you IV administer genetic
medicine? And then you could segue to
because there's there's a good drug.
>> Yeah.
>> And there are lots of good drugs that
die. Why do they die? Because they're
never going to actually make it into
production, so to speak, at scale in
healthcare. And I've seen a lot of
analogies with this, and I won't digress
too far, but with psychedelic medicine.
>> Yeah.
>> And it's just like, okay, you need like
an overnight nurse. This is going to be
an eight-hour experience or six-hour
experience.
And [snorts] sure, you could argue that
you might have the rich people pay
$10,000 out of pocket and that
subsidizes the it's sort of like Uber
Black subsidizing Uber X. Like there is
an application there, but if it's
fundamentally
incompatible with current healthcare,
you're trying to win a race with your
ankles tied together, right? It's
probably not going to happen. And then
you have people looking at like 5 DMT
instead of psilocybin and stuff. And I
have my own thoughts on that. But sure,
it's like you look at the failure just
real quick of like MDMMA assisted
psychotherapy when it got in front of
the FDA advisory committee. A lot of
reasons for that. But then you have
people coming out of the game, they're
like, "Oh, we tried to couple they tried
to couple psychotherapy with it. The FDA
does not regulate psychotherapy. It
became a huge quagmire of just like
confusion. And therefore, these other
people are like, well, let's do
methylone. It has a much shorter
halflife. You can actually fit it into
like an hour hypothetically, right? you
can decouple the therapy. We're just
looking at drug effects and lo and
behold, like it's making a ton more
progress, right? But the point of saying
all that is that you've got the kind of
SpaceX, you segue to like the holy grail
and then like what if you could
reprogram cells in the body, right? Like
what happens? So I do love the fired up
handwavy delivery thing, right? Because
you're like what they've missed is and
I'm again I'm ad libing here so it might
be [__] It's like
>> No, no, I love it.
>> They're right and they're wrong. They're
wrong because of reasons X, Y, and Z,
right? And this is a lot of hand wavy
stuff. And like
>> we're still at a point where we're
defining triple negative breast cancer
by what it isn't. It's like if you have
trouble with your shoulder and you're
like, well, good news, it's not
elephantitis and it's not Parkinson's
disease. And you're like, how does that
help me? It doesn't really, right? But
then you say they are right about
delivery in the sense that like if you
cannot plug this into health care and
deliver it to end patients game over
like it doesn't matter how effective it
is in an N of one or an N of five or
whatever your small clinical is. And the
idea these are not necessarily in the
order but talking about like even though
it's not the end goal what if we could
turn cancer into a chronic disease it
can be managed right and it's like back
in fill in the blank 1980x
right HIV was a death sentence y
>> and no longer the case now you look at
on television and it's like you see ad
after ad related to some preventative
but also like maintenance drugs that
allow people to live with a chronic
So anyway, those are a few things that
kind of hop to mind. I would be curious,
I mean for policy makers, what are the
things that most catch their attention
whether from experience or
hypothetically, right? Like what is it
that actually gets their attention?
>> I was in DC yesterday, right? And my
overarching message is sort of like
there are two things we need to to do
better. We have to build regulations
that I think are common sense that still
allow us to like more more cheaply test
drugs right now for a lot of reasons. We
have sort of vestigual over many years
reasons as to why it takes us a lot of
money and a lot of time to just get to a
simple answer on a medicine, right? And
that is creating a world in which the
biotechnology industry is incentivized
to do very small steps forward because
the cost of failure is so high that
you're trying to reduce your risk in a
way that is let's make a drug that's 10%
better right because you know taking a
truly innovative risk would be very
difficult to underwrite for for certain
investors. I'd say at the other side,
you know, the thing that catches folks
attention is to talk about how medicine
is fundamentally changing and we all can
see that AI is changing, how business is
done, how people build things, how
people read things, how people parse
through information. It's making highly
motivated people 10x better if not more.
And it's not just AI and biio medicine.
It's sort of multiple threads coming
together of novel technologies of how we
build medicines, genetic medicines and
their sort of advancements. Things like
what we're bringing forward, our ability
to diagnose diseases and subcategorize
diseases and change the way in which we
interpret, you know, how this disease
is, the sequencing technologies which
allow us to do that and other sorts of
computation and AI that plugs into those
pieces. All of that's going to
fundamentally change medicine.
>> Yeah. Because if I can't just make a
decision around the drug that every
breast cancer patient gets and then I
agree on the cost that that drug is and
I pay for it a number of years and then
the drug goes to generic and someone
brings the next drug forward that's 25%
better and blah blah blah and we just
continue along that that's the
non-inovative way in which we've been
developing medicines for for the past
number of years and every once in a
while we have a breakthrough. I'd say
policy makers tend to like that because
well it comes down to like numbers and
medicine is a very interesting piece in
policy.
>> What do they like? Could you just say
that again? They like the idea of
breakthrough versus incremental.
>> They like trying to learn about it. Like
when you start to talk about medicine,
it's very interesting because you think
about paying for medicine like the
government or health insurer, but the
government paying for medicine is a
near-term cost center that that should
long-term reduce a larger cost center,
right? So brandame medicines are 8% of
US health care spending,
>> but hospitals are 26% something like
that in the high 20s I believe. And so
you imagine that like for eight% of your
dollar in health care spending, you are
pulling down the amount of people that
are now hospitalized. You are increasing
people's life. You're keeping people in
the workforce. You're keeping people in
their homes. You're keeping people out
of a system that, you know, no one wants
to go to the hospital and and the
government that pays for a lot of
people's hospitalization in the form of
Medicare and Medicaid doesn't want to
pay for people to go to the hospital.
And so you begin to talk about that
system and you say preventative
healthcare, but all medicine to a
certain extent can be thought of as
preventative. If it's able to save off,
you know, hospitalization, it's at least
at the very least hopefully preventing
you from being in the hospital. And so
policy makers like those conversations.
I'm going to try to keep this from like
sounding too conspiracy theory, but what
what I'd love to know is what's in it
for policy makers to help you. And that
might sound strange, right? Because I'm
not saying these are bad people and we
could talk about the kind of industrial
regulatory exchange programs another
time, but that's a thing. So I guess
what I'm wondering is how do you how do
you align incentives with policy makers
so that they feel compelled and
interested in being helpful? So let's
just say there are thousand policy
makers listening right now or if you're
in the room but like what is your ask if
they're like hey look again good news
bad news bad news is I can't meet again
I'm just too busy. Good news is if you
have a reasonable ask I can green light
it right now right? Yeah,
>> but you need to do it. What is the ask?
>> My first ask right now is we need to
streamline how we test new medicines in
humans in clinical trials. In fact,
maybe if this ever sees the light at
day, hopefully the op-ed that I wrote on
accelerating first in human trials and
becoming a more innovative powerhouse as
a country.
>> Oh, where is that?
>> I just wrote it a couple weeks ago.
Okay, got it.
>> And submitted it to a handful of of
places in the last couple of days. I
think that it's the single greatest
advancement in biio medicine that we're
going to be able to make. And it of
course it opens a lot of doors for us as
strand because we have way more ideas
than we have the resources, time, and
money to take forward at $50 million a
try.
>> But if you start to make it more simple
and a lot of these things are common
sense regulations. We're we're spending
way too much time and way too much money
doing things that I think are
>> quite antiquated and vestigial in our
regulatory process. And so if you can
reduce that time and reduce the amount
of money, then you can change the
economics and the incentives around
building new drugs and you can begin to
generate more diverse data that allows
you to train things like AI models on,
you know, what actually makes a
difference in a drug and a human. We
just don't have enough data. We don't
have enough diversity of data to be able
to train them nearly to the level that
we want right now. And a lot of it just
at the end of the day, it comes down to
like does this do something in a human?
You can do all you want in the lab. You
can do all you want in mice. You can do
all you want in primate studies.
Whatever it is that you do, it just
doesn't matter to nearly the same level
until you do it with a human. And when
Janentech and Genzyme were coming up in
the 80s and 90s, it was a comically
fraction of the cost and time that it
takes to bring new medicines forward
today. This isn't a impossible thing.
we've just created a lot of weird
barriers and we need to get back to a
first principles way of thinking within
government as well. I'm not the only
person preaching that and I'm certainly
not the only one in policy that that
thinks about it. I'd say in America we
want to be the headquarters of
innovation, but a lot of other countries
want to be innovative too, right? In
Asia and in the Middle East, there are
countries that are like, we can do this.
We have the technology. We can make
investments into the space. we can make
investments into companies earlier that
we think have a high leverage point in
the future health [clears throat]
>> and we want to you know go in those
directions. The United States is is able
to do it too but that's it right?
>> If you did an 8020 analysis on the
impediments and someone's like okay we
want to streamline but if there are 10
items on your wish list let's pick two
or three. What are those two or three?
One I think is that we should remove the
FDA from a direct permissionbased
oversight organization on the beginning
of first in human trials. So let me just
explain this for like a different sort
of of audience, right? Right now in
order to do a clinical trial of what we
call a first in human, the first time
you give a drug to a human, a new drug,
right? So a phase one, in order to do
that in the United States right now, you
need to write an IND, which is called an
initial new drug application to the FDA.
It's very long. I think ours for our
first trial was 22,000 pages long.
[laughter]
>> It costs just to write it. You have to
have professional writers,
professionalized system, all sorts of
very expensive things just to write it.
It's millions of dollars.
>> Wow.
>> The studies that need to go into it are
millions of dollars. The manufacturing
of your drug and the associated
analytics of your drug in order to be
correct in the document cost millions of
dollars. And this tax up and up and up
and up and up and all of a sudden this
application cost you $25 million and it
takes 18 months to put together. Mhm.
>> Now, in China and in Australia, two of
the countries that do much faster first
in human trials than the United States,
they have a system where you go to
something to the hospitals called the
IRB, the investigational review board.
In Australia, they have a lot of
professional centralized IRBs that, you
know, manage multiple hospitals and they
they work in like a for-profit system to
help companies figure out whether or not
they're going to be a fit for the
hospital. And you still have to do that
in the United States. After you get the
IND approved by the FDA, you then have
to go to the IRBs.
And so right now since it costs so much
money and takes so much time to get an
IND from the FDA, if you have decided to
do that instead of go to Australia and
go directly to the IRBs in Australia or
go to China, your board wants you to
essentially go to the top hospitals.
Hey, if we're spending 25 million on an
IND, I want you to go to MDA Anderson. I
want you to go to Sloan Kettering. I
don't want you to go to, you know,
random pick a random great but random
hospital in the Midwest. Right? So now
we have a lot of hospitals in the United
States not running first in human
clinical trials, which means we have a
lot of Americans who exhaust their
standard of care and can't get, you
know, the access to drugs maybe before
they are fully approved and they're just
out of options unless they want to fly
to Houston or New York or Philly or
something like that. And a lot of people
don't if they're, you know, facing the
end of life or for all sorts of reasons,
people don't want to do that. And so you
have Americans not having access to
drugs. You have companies shoved into
clinical trial sites that are already
overburdened. You have IRBs at those
hospitals which are difficult to deal
with and also overburdened and like
trying to process all the people who are
trying to come through their sites
doors. And all of this is taking place
after you've spent way too much money
and way too much time submitting a
safety document to the FDA in order for
them to approve it when the FDA actually
has a lot better things to do as well.
>> Mhm.
>> And so all of that reeks of an
inefficient system.
>> So if they said got it, problem sounds
terrible like you can author the
solution. What is the alternative? So
the alternative is to allow the
hospitals and their IRBs to make the
they already make the decision on
whether or not to run a trial and
they're assessing the safety of you know
the data that you have on your safety as
well as your efficacy and the sort of
patients you want to go after. The IRB
is going to assess that and make a call
after you get the IND done. I think the
the transition system to transition to
is what Australia calls it as a CTN.
It's a clinical trial notification
system. you notify the regulators, hey,
we're going to run a trial. It's not a
pass system. There are exceptions.
Certain types of drugs still need to go
through them for like formal approval,
but for the most part, you can notify
them, go to the IRB, the IRB can say,
"Yep, we think this is safe enough." And
the reason that is still a very safe
option because patient safety from a
drug company perspective, from
everyone's perspective, is number one.
There is nothing that will kill your
company faster. There is nothing that
will you know just make me never be able
to sleep again. It would be harming
patients especially harming patients
because you are being sloppy. And the
group that cares obviously cares just as
much if not more than everyone else is
the hospital's review board because the
hospital does not want patients harmed
or dying god forbid in their trials.
Right? The FDA isn't magical in their
oversight of safety, but you distribute
this workload across the IRBs that exist
throughout the United States. And they
get certified with the FDA to be able to
approve this. You can centralize the IRB
so that you know individual hospitals
don't have to have their own IRB. You
can have all of these systems. And now
all of a sudden, you have hospitals that
have the ability to attract
biotechnology companies for for drug
trials.
>> Yeah. It takes infrastructure to run
clinical trials. And so the free market
sort of picks up there and builds a
system that I think can accelerate
clinical trial management. And you free
the FDA to focus on the things that
matter, which is approving drugs based
on efficacy and safety. That's how drugs
get approved.
>> Mhm. I know you got to run a bit, but
>> we can chat again, too. This is fun. We
don't talk enough.
>> Yeah. This is a juicy piece, so I want
to chew on it a little bit more.
>> Yeah. So I've funded a bunch of science
in
mostly New Zealand but also in a few
other countries simply because the speed
of cutting through red tape and the
sheer amount of red tape is much less.
So that's why I would choose like a New
Zealand and some of these very credible
universities over like doing research.
No offense to Jamaica, but it's like
there's psychedelic stuff going on in
Jamaica, but it's like nobody in the US
gives a [__] right? They're not going
to listen. It's not going to hold
anyone's attention. Yeah.
>> And I guess what I'm wondering is
simultaneously I can look at a New
Zealand and say, "Okay, it's mostly
sheep. Yeah, you have some people, but
it's a lot easier to run New Zealand
than it is to run the United States." So
I can't just say this works in New
Zealand, copy and paste into the United
States. Australia is is substantially
larger, right? So I guess two questions.
The first is like 0 to 10 confidence.
What is your confidence level that if
policymakers got behind it that
something could be done along those
lines? Not necessarily even at the
federal level, maybe at a state level. I
mean, there's all sorts of complexity
there, but what's your confidence level
that something like that could be
implemented in the US within the I don't
know what the time frame would be, the
next 5 years, let's just say 5 to 10
years if policy makers got behind it.
And [snorts] then the the correlary to
that is is there any competition for
scientific innovation that is attractive
to a company like Strand much like
companies are moving from say California
to Texas, right? because there are
certain incentives.
>> Is there a competition for talent
globally through which if the UAE wants
to greenlight something incredibly
quickly and fund it that Strand would be
interested or is it live or die, ride or
die in the United States for any host of
different reasons, right? I know some
companies who have tried to tackle the
FDA first because they're like, "Hey,
once we have this data, we can kind of
copy and paste a lot of it into the EMA
in Europe, which is the sort of
equivalent."
I know that's a lot that I just threw
out there, but what are your thoughts?
>> So, to answer the first question,
there's a global competition for running
clinical trials like this, and actually
what we are in the midst of right now is
the United States massively losing to
China. China has built a an
industrialized
version of clinical trial infrastructure
for first in human trials that is so
efficient and massively quick that
they're just able to go faster and
cheaper into the thing that matters most
which is first in human trials. And so
the United States is actually in the
process of very rapidly as a country
falling behind China because what
started as a place for American
companies to come run clinical trials to
get data and then take it to the FDA and
then do larger trials in the United
States has now created a flywheel
structure within China where now just
Chinese companies run their clinical
trials faster than the American
companies and then bring their Chinese
discovered drugs to the United States.
And what happens is the capital flow the
risk capital then says ah these
companies are more efficient I will fund
these sorts of of aspects and so there's
always state by state we want to have
biotechnology here every state's always
tried to have it I'd say just like AI
tech like the best technologies remain
in like Boston and San Francisco just
tech companies might have left for Miami
and Texas but like where's open AI right
it's in San Francisco
>> yeah right
>> you know all due respect to Austin and
Miami I love those cities But you know,
San Francisco, it's hard to replicate
those pieces. And biotechnology,
Boston's really dominated a lot of it
for the past 30 years. Though in this
new age of medicine, I'd say San
Francisco is really rivaling Boston
because the risk capital and the
openness to like radical new ideas is
much higher. I think that also attracts
a healthy amount of like hype no
substance companies and hype no
substance founders and technologies. But
I think that's a low price to pay to
like take some big swings at like what
could be transformational technologies.
Even though I run a company in Boston, I
love Massachusetts. I personally
identify with that ethos a little bit
more of like if some [__] hype
filters into this, it's worth it in
order to take the correct swings at the
truly big ideas because one out of 10
transformations is better than seven out
of 10 logical steps forward. So CTN in
the US like some version of that. Yeah.
As you described in Australia, if you
were a betting man, right? If you were
like, "Okay, I'm going to go on poly
market and I'm going to put half my net
worth on a bet." I guess I'm asking you,
how possible or impossible is the task
of retrofitting the FDA and approval
processes.
>> This is not a comment on politics and
this is also not a comment on like a lot
of different things that are happening
at the FDA right now. But I will say in
terms of the last 10 years of the FDA,
the time to which they would be open to
such a radical transformation and
radical in government bureaucracies
terms, right? The thing about government
bureaucracies is they very rarely seed
their oversight. They will take new
things to be oversight of, but like in
general regulatory anything takes a This
is the problem with nuclear energy in
America for the past 30 years. It's like
we just tack on one more thing and one
more thing and one more thing and one
more thing and these cottage industries
emerge to support the giant regulatory
machinery and we don't take a step back
to be like why are we doing this? At the
same time I'd say to look at the FDA
right now this is probably the most open
I've seen people to the idea of like we
want the FDA to be an exceptional
regulatory body. We want them to build
regulatory sciences that give us
ultimate confidence in like the drugs
that we build. But there are new
technologies that we've been slow to
implement. There have been markets that
haven't been able to be fully created
with technology for things like clinical
trial analysis because no one was sure
if the FDA would embrace them. And there
are things such as like early stage
safety which are already handled by
hospitals themselves where it will take
some time to make. But if I was a
betting man, I'd say I I give it a 50%
likelihood that in the next, you know,
two years we can get to this. I wouldn't
be spending my time talking to policy
makers about an idea
to like a senator. This is like I
believe that this is possible. I believe
that we can do this. I believe if we
don't do it, it is actually existential.
Like we will lose a lot of our ability
to develop drugs in America over the
next few years to China if we don't do
it because capital has no allegiance,
right?
>> Yeah. I also believe that there's other
countries and especially you know the
UAE for example are ones that are
watching it carefully and going hey like
we have great technology we have a great
landing place for western you know for a
lot of western values and western
companies we have great quality of life
here we could attract folks to come do
innovative work here
>> and so when I hear various different
leaders of countries in the Middle East
talk about it I certainly think it's
possible because they are countries at
least over the last 10 years where
you've seen be able to make aggressive
bets in certain directions in order to
attract innovation and you know so if
they were able to do that then yeah I
mean these sorts of things could
radically transform how people think
about developing medicines and at the
end of the day if we are able to develop
better medicines quicker faster cheaper
more ambitiously
everyone wins
>> yeah I've been so impressed with the
speed at which the department of health
in say Abu Dhabi or UAE even more
broadly speaking but it's incredible
>> how ambitious they are but in addition
to that how willing they are to take big
swings and accelerate things
unbelievably
>> that's the country we've spoken to the
least in the Middle East I will say
though I know that they have you know I
mean it's connections and it's spending
the time trying to decide like what
people want to do
>> y
>> I'm a believer in allied countries
coming together we run our trials in the
United States and Australia. I think
countries that share very similar values
on like the future of of the world need
to come together to build like
innovative solutions to the massive
problems facing us as like a human
species. It's not every country though.
>> No, it's not every country. Anything you
want to talk about just in the last
however many minutes we have?
>> I've actually taken a lot of way of I
don't know responding to how you're
responding to different pieces of the
story, right? I think I view it as
important to sort of tell the world
about this innovation and whether that
means finding the large sovereign
wealths of the world that are going to
help us like right now we are as a
company everything is working within our
technology stack. We sit here and look
at these problems of like gosh to use a
bad analogy it feels like Sophie's
choice sometimes around like how we're
going to prioritize what we're going to
work on. We can't work on everything.
The other overused analogy is robbing
Peter to pay Paul, right? It's like,
okay, this feels like I wish this wasn't
zero sum, but I have, you know, if we
look at what our technology can do
today, I look across and I'm like, okay,
we want to work on cancer, we want to
work on autoimmune disease, but also
like kidney is really interesting and oh
my god, we could do so much good if we
applied this in the crisper space and
all of these things. And so what I've
been trying to spend the last 6 months
and my time thinking about is like what
is the correct model for us to make sure
we are doing our diligence of advancing
medicine at the fastest rate we possibly
can.
>> There are so many different things that
we strand can work on. We need to find
various different partners. Sometimes
that's pharma partners that are like
we're interested in this disease area
and and it's very simple because the
biotech and pharma companies work
together all the time on partnerships.
But I'd say, you know, what's really
interesting is this opportunity, you
know, this global opportunity and this
broader opportunity to say like we could
do all of these different diseases.
We're we're fighting a resource
constraint at all times. So, how do we
find other people who want to
participate with us both intellectually
and capitalally with capital that can
help us build various different
solutions? Whether that's for diabetes,
whether that's for polycystic kidney
disease, whether that's for all sorts of
other indications throughout the world.
It'll take novel scientific models
because what we are doing is is
scientifically novel. So we'll need
different sorts of business models to
think about this. But you said something
earlier about my like frustration with
biotech's ambitions sometimes. And I
think it's just like God the Janentech
and Genzyme people used to do insane
things. Genzyme used to drive around
Boston collecting placentas from the
hospitals. They had a van called the
placenta mobile. They would pick up
placentas and then use them to purify a
protein that they were turning into a
drug for a rare disease. It was like the
ultimate founder mode of how do we stop
this disease? And somehow we're now
like, well, I don't know what would that
look like from a TPP and if FDA won't
think about a proven mechanism and it's
just [__] exhausting. [laughter] We
got to just get our entrepreneurial
pants back on and like try to fix
disease. So, I've just taken the few
minutes you gave me and diet trib
[laughter]
like more interesting conversations for
us to have on and off recording. Tim, I
love talking to you. You're just fun,
man. So,
>> yeah, we'll do more. We didn't even
really get into the platform aspect of
things. I I used the space X analogy of,
you know, the sort of
>> first [snorts] principles
engineering payload agnostic platform,
right? We didn't even really get into
the platform. Are you leaning away or
leaning into the
>> kind of programming reprogrammable
>> language of around Strand? I'm leaning
away from the words programmable or
programming within there because
>> they get people confused about what a
what a platform is. Like in my new deck,
it ends actually with this piece of like
what Strand is, right? Strand is a
flywheel of various technologies, AI
models, manufacturing expertise like
talent that we have, you know, trade
secret, all these pieces that create a
flywheel of how we build platforms for
areas of the body that we want to
access. That's the platforms, right? So
tumor delivery is a platform. T- cell
delivery is a platform. We want to build
more of those platforms over time. We
build them as drugs like the ST00003
that's coming to the clinic this year 6
months ahead of schedule. That is a
drug, but it is a platform for tumors.
It's not a platform for everything you
want to do throughout the body. And
that's where people got lost. I think
that's where Madna got lost. They
thought your tumor platform also worked
for your liver worked for the kidney. We
could do everything with one platform.
It's just not true. And so what I've
been trying to do is help people
understand it. And it's the SpaceX
analogy kind of works well within this
because SpaceX over time built different
platforms for different use cases that
were more and more complex and took more
and more time and knowledge and they
used the learning. So Falcon 1 was able
to get single satellites up. It took
them a while to figure it out, but they
were able to perfect the landing and the
recovery and the reusability of a rocket
that was useful, but it wasn't super
useful. Then they had Falcon Heavy. They
were like, "Now we can take multiple
things up or we could take large
payloads up. We could take astronauts up
to the space station. We could do all of
these things." Then they have Starship,
right? Which is you can't start with
Starship. Even Elon 20 years ago being
one of the greatest fundraisers and
visionaries couldn't go, we're going to
build Starship. That's our first
product. You got to build the Tesla
Roadster to get to the Model 3. You got
to find the first minimal viable product
that does matter and helps you get your
feet under yourself. And that's what our
first drug was. And now we're building
more and more ambitious things. I don't
mind talking about a platform because I
can scientifically prove we have a tumor
platform. I can show you the data,
right? We have a T- cell platform. I can
show you the data of how we can swap
things in for the T- cell. Whatever you
want to put in a T- cell, we'll put into
a T- cell. Doesn't matter. But it's for
a T- cell, right? And we want to build
more platforms over time. That's where I
think where we need the most help of
like, you know, finding novel business
models, partners throughout the globe
who are like interested.
>> Yeah.
>> I don't mind it. I don't mind it anymore
because we can defend it.
>> Yeah. Totally. Getting satellites into
orbit is different from getting to the
moon, which is different from getting to
Mars. Right.
>> Yeah. And injecting things into tumors
is different than getting things to
deliver to tumors autonomously through
the bloodstream, which is different than
getting to TE- cells, which is different
than getting to your kidney, which is
different than getting to your brain.
Like those are all different things and
they will be bigger and bigger
opportunities for us.
And now we get to part two. This is the
second conversation with Jake. This is
roughly two months later and a lot
happened between the first and second
recordings. Jake's op-ed ran. We did a
ton of split testing and behind
the-scenes work. The conversation around
clinical trials and US competitiveness
reached new levels of traction, got in
front of new audiences, and ultimately
made its way, let's just call it
metaphorically, to the Oval Office. And
we will get into all of it. So, this
next section is a follow-up. What
happened after the first conversation,
what Jake learned from the response, and
how he's thinking about the bigger story
of Strand and the future of medicine. We
get into a lot of fun stuff in this
section. Please enjoy. So Jake, we first
recorded
brainstorming and you had a lot
wellformed different approaches to
messaging [clears throat]
and then we stopped recording but at
that point you had a pending or
hopefully pending oped. Could you just
walk us through what transpired after
that? Yeah. So, we're working on the
message of course and how to frame this
so that people could digest what needs
to happen and sort of both what needs to
happen fundamentally but also the
urgency of it. So, after that the
Washington Post actually placed it in
their op-ed column and it really I think
went viral at least through you know a
lot of biotech and medical policy
communities. I sort of saw it spread its
way across is you know a number of
people thought either I never heard this
idea it's a fantastic idea to start or I
never heard that there was this sort of
pressing risk to you know our biio
medical industrial base going overseas
to China and you know the US is sort of
contributing to it by getting in our own
way. So after that, you and I really sat
down and thought about like what's
working with the piece. And the piece
was pretty fully baked. And you know,
when you put something in the Washington
Post, you don't have all the control
over the full message. There are many
other professional publicists and folks
involved in that endeavor, which is
totally fine. I'm just a lowly
scientist. But
at the end of the day, you and I started
sitting and and talking about like,
okay, but what what grabs people's
attention? How do we drive people into
the bulk of the message? How do we make
people care so that they'll pick up the
message? And that was really helpful
because about a day after the op-ed ran,
a member of a congressional staff had
reached out and said, "We're putting
together a hearing on the hill around
the risk to the, you know, biomedical
industrial supply
chain and biomedical industry in the
United States in relation to what's
going overseas to China and how
competition is shaping up and sort of
degrading our ability to develop
medicines here in the United States. And
so as we sort of talked through that
idea, it really helped because we saw
what was working with the piece, we saw
what was confusing about the piece and
we saw, you know, maybe what was maybe
not bad, but what was helpful or better
or caused more engagement or, you know,
ABC testing and all of a sudden A is 90%
of the click-through options. And so
once we sort of saw that and I think one
of the things that surprised me the most
about it, maybe it shouldn't be
surprising, but the opportunistic tone
of like this is the problem, but we can
fix it. Maybe it should be obvious, but
that's the one that sort of got us
going. And so when I went down to the
hill about a week and a half after the
piece ran, that's how we reframed the
whole story, which is a much more
productive way to get politicians to
care about something, right? If you if
you come to them and you say
everything's bad and it's burning and
we're done. Honestly, what is anyone
going to do?
>> Yeah.
>> But coming with reframing it and being
upfront about like bad things are
happening, but we can fix them. It's in
your power. Let's go.
>> Was was taken up very well. And so
between the testimony and a number of
meetings after that that day around DC,
we really started to form a sort of
fervor. And you know, fast forward to
about 2 weeks ago, the president put out
his policy objectives, his legislative
objectives. And in those legislative
objectives, in fact, you sort of the
president recommends what he thinks the
budget should look like and then
Congress takes it up and then actually
bakes it into it
>> for policy sequencing. But in the
president's recommendations, there is
this exact idea of of removing
barriers to getting early stage
experimental medicines to American
patients in America through FDA reform.
And that's an incredibly quick
turnaround for Washington DC, which I
think should inspire all of us to get
more involved.
>> All right, [clears throat] so let me add
to the recap. Thank you for that.
>> So we got on the phone. I was in Utah at
the time. I remember very different
background had our first recording
talking about the message spitballing
stuff around then you published the
op-ed in the Washington Post afterwards
came out and the piece I pulled it up
very wellbaked edited piece the headline
was the US can't afford to offshore
clinical trials to China a burdensome
regulatory environment is pushing
clinical trials overseas and when I saw
that I was like okay this may be the
best of all possible options, but let's
test that. And to your point, right,
there are a lot of stakeholders, a lot
of people involved. And also, people are
busy, right? So, if they've got 50
stories to put out, once they've done
the work on one, they don't necessarily
want to go back and have to fiddle and
fuss with every headline that they've
put out, but internally grabbed it and
had someone on my team go to a site
called Pikfu. We're not going to get
into the branding of Pikfu.
>> [laughter]
>> But pfu.com, which is sort of human plus
AI helping you to split test. It could
be an image. It could be the cover of a
board game in my case or a card game. It
could also be a headline. And the
purpose for doing that, since people
listening might think, well, there's so
many stakeholders, you know, they're not
going to change it. Why even bother?
It's because we got five different
options. And you and I were texting. I
was like, what what do you think of
these six options? and you're like,
"These are the two of the things that
internally would come up with that you
liked." It's like, "Okay, well, let's
only split test those because otherwise,
what's the point?" Cuz the intention
behind it is not to change the headline,
but to then take messaging and emphasis
that you can use in person, right, or
otherwise, or on stage in terms of
framing. So the fact that you had
everything lined up to then have the,
you know, refined story for
congressional testimony and then to
ultimately get to the big office. It's
pretty fun. It's a really fun
compression of things. And I should also
I suppose just as a recap for folks
highlight that what we ended up talking
about a lot towards the end of the
conversation was just not simplifying
the message for people but how do you
simplify it and make it appealing for
policy makers specifically and that's
how the text conversation unfolded
around and this is also for those people
are writing non-fiction books whenever
there's a book that's like why kids are
all depressed and it's only getting
worse, you're kind of like, ah, do I
really want to spend 200 pages reading
about that problem? But if it's like why
kids are all depressed and it's not the
only way, then you're like, oh, okay,
there's actually potentially not a pot
of gold at the end of the rainbow, but
some type of prescription or
recommendation for fixing the situation,
then
the the response rate tends to be a lot
higher.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
>> So, where do things stand now? Like, how
do you feel about the messaging? And you
know me, I'm like the person who likes
to think of himself as smart but
nonetheless ends up asking dumb
questions over and over and over again.
But in terms of messaging, how happy are
you with the messaging? And we can
obviously bat things around. And then
are the policy makers still the sort of
primary target for your personal
external comms because the regulatory
hurdles and like the molasses on the
ground when you're trying to push things
through is so slow still compared to
China or Australia let's say.
>> Yeah. So the idea itself I mean from our
first conversation that was only
I don't know two months ago not even
>> yeah not even
>> we sort of had this conversation this is
important fast forward two months
>> the president puts out
>> legislative priorities to Congress that
has the message inside of it.
>> I'd say I'm pretty happy with that sort
of timeline of [laughter]
movement.
>> Yeah. And I think that what we
successfully did with the story [snorts]
was
the bad part of it that's h is like this
is happening, this is bad and driving
urgency of like this isn't a let's have
12 more hearings. This is a we either
fix this today or we get comfortable
with only getting all of our medicines
developed in China or discovered in
China and then the United States will
just pay the bill. So two months is an
incredibly quick time for really any
amount of legislative progress. I mean,
it's it's still not done. It's still not
baked. It still needs, you know, these
things need to be codified. The FDA
needs to actually adapt them. But I'd
say that's
>> a lot of positive forward progress. And
shaping the story around like here is
the solution upfront I think helped us
really tie folks in. One of the things I
learned in trips to DC over the past
year is a lot of people go down and are
like complaining and it's very hard.
People will hear you out because that's
what you do to a constituent if you're
in public office. You're like this is
okay. I'm sorry that that happened. But,
you know, it's really more like being a
policy shoulder to cry on than getting
anything done. And so going with, you
know, this is a problem. This is the
urgency. it needs your attention and
here is a solution or part of the
solution and moving our narrative
between hacking it out with you moving
the narrative to bring the solution up
front I think helps people not tune out
immediately from like to understand what
someone's bringing you a story with
we've talked about this in larger pieces
of stories which is how do you bring
your focus and your hook up front to me
I like as a scientist I like to drill
down to the whole piece and like explain
all the details to people and all the
reasons why something is is maybe [__]
and instead I think it's better to just
start with like hey things things aren't
going great but there is a solution and
then if you want now that you care a
little bit and you see a light at the
end of the tunnel now we can go through
the whole process you can understand the
nuance of like both what's happening
what we can do and how we get to the
other side it's almost like you know
when I talk to technologists who are
building other companies like mine and
try to help scientists understand how to
pitch even to other technical investors.
The thing I always come back to is no
one will learn until they care. So your
first goal is to make someone care about
what you're doing. Then they'll learn.
Scientists are very spoiled because when
you sit around with a bunch of
scientists and talk science, they all
care. [laughter] It's a science thing.
Scientists, they're implicitly like,
"Oh, wow. You study black holes and the
gravity at the center of them. Like
that's so interesting." You don't have
to motivate it. There doesn't have to be
a reason. The reason is wow. Like cool.
And at MIT when I was there for 6 years,
it was very spoiled environment because
I'd be like, I'm working on, you know,
the future of RNA medicine and how RNAs
are programmable. And they'd go, "Wow,
tell me more." And then you go out to an
investor or have dinner with Tim Ferrris
and you got to like wheel it back and be
like, "Why does this even matter besides
being a footnote on genetics?" And I
think [clears throat] that's always a
good learning and it's something I've
gotten used to with like talking about
my company and talking about what we're
doing. But then coming back to policy,
it just helped drive it back to me that
like this is a fundamental truth of
storytelling.
>> Yeah.
>> If you're trying to get something done,
make someone care, explain the problem,
illustrate a solution, and then help
them then they can go a level deeper. We
could talk about the specifics and the
pathway there.
>> Yeah, for sure. And the storytelling
word and this is important because if
you're if you're proilitizing, if you're
persuading,
in almost every instance, it's going to
be some form of storytelling. So after
the op-ed came out, after you giving
your congressional testimony, etc.,
etc., you also sent me a few different
docs. Yeah,
>> there was the investor update doc which
we may not get into great detail on
depending on like how much needs to be
redacted, but we can we can always bleep
it out or cut it.
>> Yeah.
>> The second was sort of a primer on mRNA
and programmable medicine if that's fair
to describe it.
>> Yeah.
>> And one of the edit notes which is a
suggestion. I mean I'm not right about
everything but I was like you know what
in the second piece
there's the story of
Alphold and I was like that's a great
place to start because sometimes if you
begin with high concept or you begin
with things that are a little abstract
it's easy for people to get lost even if
they understand it for it to cause them
to drift. And so it's like okay maybe
start with story point story or like you
know sure you could start with like a
shocking stat and then lead into like
here's the problem here's the solution.
There are a lot of ways to do it, but
the storytelling piece, it's easy for
people to forget that selling, pitching,
board meeting, like you name it, a lot
of it is going to revolve around your
ability to tell compelling stories. So,
where would you like to go next? I mean,
I grabbed of course a whole bunch of
things. And before this call, I sent you
my kind of edit notes as images that I
scanned, but also as a loom where I kind
of walked through my thinking behind
some of those edit notes. I wanted to
actually before we move to that make a
quick note for people mentioning Pikfu.
I don't have a any uh equity in Pikfu.
[laughter] I just like saying it
actually which is like I could make fun
of the name but it's like the fact of
the matter is I just think it's
hilarious to say. The other application
or value of the split testing is not
just having maybe a better idea of
oneliners or framing that you could use
in person. Because even though the
headline of the op-ed couldn't be
changed, when I then shared that
article,
I was able to use the same link, sure,
but I was able to use a different
headline based on the split testing. And
it was unambiguous. It was like one or
two of the headlines
tested were by far and away the winners,
statistically speaking. And so it's
like, all right, just grab that because
ultimately top of the funnel, you need
click-through rate before people are
ever going to read the piece. So let's
optimize for that. But coming back to I
guess where to go next, you tell me,
man, this is this is in service of
whatever you think might be worthwhile
to go over. So what are your thoughts?
So when we move back to the longer piece
that I've been just trying to organize
some of my thoughts around where I think
at least a piece of the future of
medicine is heading.
>> Let me pause here for one second. So the
working headline is RNA medicine and the
rise of platform therapeutics.
>> Yes.
>> Okay. Go ahead. Just wanted to give
people something to hang their head on.
So RNA medicine and the rise of platform
therapeutics and thinking about what
even introducing to the world what a
platform therapy or a therapeutic
platform could be, why it changes
medicine, why it changes how we think
about developing medicines, deploying
medicines in the near-term, the
medium-term and the long term, right?
Where are we going? You know, what could
be in the clinic next year
>> because of this technology? What could
be possible with medicine in 5 years?
And then where are we on a 10 to 15 year
time curve in terms of what will will be
possible and I've been trying to
organize some thoughts around this the
way that I see the future. The policy
piece of this story over the top is an
important aspect of it because you know
biotechnology and space rocket companies
I think are actually two of the most
similar industries out there. You have
an incredibly long time horizon on
investment. You have an incredibly high
upfront investment cost and you have
essentially binary outcomes. The drug
works or it doesn't. You get to orbit or
you don't. You blow up on takeoff or you
fail some [snorts] early stage safety
readout. Those are all very similar.
What I think the rocket industry got out
in front of them and Elon as sort of
the, you know, flag bearer of commercial
space industry going back to the early
2000s got out in front of this message
with was how to engage policy makers to
enable innovation to feedback on itself
in a rapid context. And so in the 2000s
it actually was just like it is today
with medicine. It was very hard to like
rapidly launch rockets. It was very hard
to fail multiple times, fail or not
completely succeed or just be given the
privilege to take shots. Now, I want to
say putting a medicine into a human is
not the same as launching a rocket that
is available to blow up over the Gulf of
Mexico and we can salvage that. We don't
want to put people's lives in danger.
But we do need common sense regulatory
reform to enable this future of
medicine. And as I sort of got to the
end of that story with you and got that
in front of Congress and got it into the
president's legislative priorities, it
turned back to this piece of where do I
see medicine going? Where do I see
platform therapeutics? And your feedback
on what I had put together is actually
helpful because one of the questions I
saw in your loom was what do you mean by
platform? What do you mean by
infrastructure? Are these the same
things or are these different? M and so
maybe it's more helpful to talk about
like what a platform therapeutic is to
start. So a therapeutic platform people
have been claiming medicines are
platforms for 20 years in the biotech
industry and they've almost always been
wrong.
>> It sounds good.
>> The reason people like it is that
theoretically if you have a platform
that is can be multiple drugs then
someone will give you a premium over the
it's like when sweet green went public
and they were like we're a tech company
not a salad company. we deserve a markup
in our market [laughter] cap and you're
like okay well I mean prove it maybe I
don't know Domino's is a tech company
and an infrastructure company so it is
possible this is like a a caffeine
ketone induced interjection but people
should go back and check out the stock
charts on Domino's Pizza compared to
like all the fancy tech companies and
everything blow your mind just put that
aside but yeah
>> I think that this doesn't happen in
biotechnology enough for the record, but
I try to be a student of like business
and innovation broadly and study like
how Elon has built SpaceX, how Domino's
has built dominoes. And that also shapes
my global worldview on hey biotechnology
is having a rare earth metals moment, a
rare earth minerals moment with China
right now. That was, you know, 1015
years ago for the electric vehicle
industry. on the Domino side like you
look at that and you go wow this is a
incredible infrastructure of tech story
of pizza that's like fine you know it's
fine I'm from Illinois near Chicago so
their pizza is like fine to me that's
the official talking point but to wheel
it back what is a platform in business
but I guess what is a platform
therapeutic so in medicine going back 50
years to the beginning of biotechnology
you started with let's design this drug
and it's a molecule. It needs to be put
together in a certain way. We do that in
the lab and then we take it forward. We
put it in a patient. We see how it works
and we move it through clinical trials.
If it's successful, then it gets
approved and then we can sell it in the
marketplace and you know then the
company finally you know makes some
amount of money. And the problem with
that just in terms of irr or
verticalization story is that the
company itself gets value because it
learns how to do the process but the
technology doesn't build on itself. So
you build one drug and you get that drug
approved. The next time you start back
at square one for either a different
medicine or a different type. Maybe you
take some learnings that you have about
that medicine. But everyone has the
learnings because we we do science in
the open. Everyone sees a lot of your
FDA documents. They see your medicine
that you're bringing forward. You have
to publish your clinical trial results
in certain forums. So you're not gaining
any sort of piece by developing it.
Though you are, you know, as a business,
you're flexing that muscle, which is
helpful and it's it's helpful to have
that experience as an organization, but
you're not decreasing the risk of future
medicines. So a platform therapeutic
seeks to build a common technological
infrastructure that you can build
multiple different medicines off of. So
an example of a platform would would
actually be Madna's RNA vaccine
platform. So people like to say this
thing about the COVID vaccine about how
how Madna built a COVID vaccine in 62
days and got it into clinical trials.
Sure, that's true. 62 days from the
identification of the COVID antigen, the
COVID sequence that they wanted to use
and then 62 days to like create a
vaccine for testing. But they spent 12
years before that developing this sort
of technology, baseline technology,
particles, RNA sequences, all these
pieces to build a lot of other types of
vaccines and therapeutics. And so when
COVID came around, they had, you know,
flu vaccine and all of these different
types of other vaccines that they knew
how they worked and they were able to
kind of plug and play in a COVID
sequence where a flu sequence used to be
and use that in that setting. And that's
very powerful in terms of speed sort of
mRNA vaccines aside and what everyone's
piece on them is. I just think that the
story of speed and the story of roll out
is really important
>> just for folks who like me are like oh
god I'm getting [snorts]
maybe not lost but I'm like this is
biotech I don't know very much about
right to come back to like the dominoes
or let's say Uber
>> or SpaceX but it's like if Uber has
built the infrastructure and everything
necessary with Uber Eats to deliver
hamburgers and then it's like can you
deliver these
vaccines. It's not the best example
because you're not going to be shipping
these to people's homes necessarily.
Yeah.
>> And they're like, "Sure." And then the
story is, you know, in 60 days Uber
developed an entire system for
delivering vaccines. It's like, well,
kind of,
>> right? [laughter]
But they had everything else already
built that enabled them to do that which
then for each additional quote unquote
launch, not to mix the SpaceX, but they
are derisking
the entire endeavor and speeding it up
by effectively skipping all of those
steps that are already established. I
would say biotechnology is I think
incredibly antiquated when it comes to
like involvement of advanced
technologies that are not biological. So
when I think about what we need to
realize the future of medicine, there's
two different buckets. One of them are
new drug technologies. So these are
programmable medicines. These are
different sorts of ways to think about
the drug that gets injected into the
person. How is that going to be more
advanced, safer, more controllable, more
adaptable, more personalizable? The
second piece is physical deployment
infrastructure. How do we build
small-cale manufacturing and clinical
supply chains that can deploy nationally
and globally to make sure that in your
neighborhood you're able to get this
advanced medicine and those are two
different important pieces to what I see
the future of medicine becoming.
And so on the therapeutic platform side,
these are new technologies. This is what
we're we're developing at Strand. We're
developing to use a SpaceX analogy,
various different types of rockets. And
so the way we're thinking about this is
you have payloads, right? similar to
satellites that SpaceX is trying to get
more and more fancy payloads,
satellites, astronauts, eventually
entire data centers or entire moonbased
crews
into orbit in an efficient manner that's
scalable for medicine. And in the same
way, what we're trying to solve is doing
that with build the technological
solutions to get these different
proteins into the different areas of the
body. And the reason that is such a
pressing problem is that right now we
have a lot of lowhanging fruit. That is
diseases. We know how to treat proteins
that we know could do something about
it, but the inability to sort of get the
protein to where it needs to go. But we
are accelerating our knowledge with AI.
You have Deep Mind and AlphaFold
creating the ability to design almost
any protein you can imagine to do
anything. you have new AI research tools
that are helping us understand disease
at a higher level of complexity. We're
very soon going to reach a massive
bottleneck of all of these different
solutions that we know exist like what
to do and we can't get them where they
need to go. We're going to have a
backlog of satellites and no ability to
get them to orbit in a scalable manner.
And so it's great to have AI tools. It's
great to build all this new technology,
but we've now taken the bottleneck that
used to be discovery and we're shifting
it over into deployment and testing.
>> What I'd love to just come back to in
case it has changed.
>> Yeah.
>> What are the blockers in the way of your
most important responsibilities as CEO
cuz it's like I want to make sure that
what we're talking about is kind of in
service of that. I think that's a
fantastic question actually because I
guess what I'm saying about what
medicine needs to have like a SpaceX
moment for instance I don't think at
least that it's a non-obvious thing to
realize the problem is how do you
actually execute it and the reality of
medicine development in the United
States and how biotech companies work in
the United States and the capital
formation ecosystem that exists to
create medicine in the United states is
incredibly swung to the incentivization
of making minor steps forward and of
doing single things at a time.
>> And so biotechnology actually in the US
is is not set up from a venture capital
standpoint in a lot of ways like
technology is. In tech, you have people
constantly being like, I'm going to
build a generational company. In
biotechnology, 90 plus% of companies go,
here's an idea. I'm gonna take it from
point A to point B, which point B is not
commercial. Point A is this is the idea
and I think it could work. And point B
is here's some evidence that it works.
And at point B, I'm going to sell the
asset. It's very similar to how people
think about real estate development, for
instance. And so it's attracted almost
like a private equity asset development
sort of mindset. Sorry to interrupt, but
like I I try to be the muggle who's
like, "Oo, that's interesting." Like
that's very memorable, but just like
current state of biotech
comparable to real estate development
for these following reasons.
>> Yeah.
>> But what would it look like for us to
have our SpaceX moment and why is that
even relevant? That contrast is super
interesting. It's the first time I've
heard you say that and like immediately
I'm like, "Oh yeah, okay, got it."
>> Well, I really think it's a capital
markets problem. Let's go back to SpaceX
again because I just love talking about
SpaceX. No one would debate in 2004
maybe that if you radically decreased
the cost to orbit per kilogram that that
would not be an incredible business. I
think that that's very obvious. The
question was both technologically and
how could we possibly get there? And
luckily we had someone who was both
already extremely wealthy. He wasn't a
billionaire yet at that point I don't
think
>> which is [__] crazy to think about.
[laughter]
>> Yeah. Elon being a lowly 130 millionaire
in the 2000s and who then just put it
all on black and was like, "Spin the
wheel, Johnny. Let's go." And then just
shot rocket. Shot rocket. Shot rocket.
I'm going to go bankrupt. Whatever. He's
like, "I'll just go back and make
another zip 2 and I'll I'll do another
tech. I'll do another PayPal if this
doesn't work out." By the way, I was a
huge space nerd at the time and in high
school following this story and
listening to like all of the
establishment voices being like, "This
guy is an idiot. He doesn't know what
he's doing, but he had both his own
capital, but the other thing about Elon
that I think everyone should be able to
tell at this point is he's an incredible
capital formation genius. He's an
incredible storyteller, which was one of
the core keys of capital formation.
>> For people listening, are we talking
about fundraising? Is that what that
means?
>> Oh, yes. Fundraising. Yeah. It's it's
about getting money around the idea. The
ability to pull tons of dollars together
around a core insane long-term mission
is an incredible skill set that deep
technology which is sort of the umbrella
that has like space and you know quantum
computing and biotechnology like
anything that is a long R&D time horizon
requires and so the capital pools the
fundraising environment that is
traditional biotech really deeply
struggles with the idea of long-term
bold idea investment. We have very few
shots that are even allowed to be taken
on goal. And so when I think about back
to your original question, what is my
goal as CEO who wants to not just build
a better biotech widget? I don't want to
build a better mousetrap to catch more
mice for this one person and exit out of
the company. We want to fundamentally
change how we're able to build
medicines. That is a long and expensive
road. And even as you unlock, you know,
if we get drugs approved and we are able
to get revenues, by the time we're
there, ideally our research engine is
humming so much that even those drug
revenues don't pay for all of our re
it's a constant like feed forward until
you break through to the other side and
all of a sudden you're staring at a
trillion dollar IPO. And so you have to
kind of like catch that. As CEO, I think
about how do we find globally the people
who are aligned with that idea? And
that's collaborators, it's financial
support, it's people who want to think
about, you know, if you're trying to get
the best irr on your dollar between here
and next year, I might not be your best
bet. I'm sorry. We might not be your
best bet. We hope to be, we always hope
to drive that original piece, but we
want to be the 10, 20, 30year massive
return that people are going to see
while we push medicine forward. And so
those capital partners, they exist. They
exist in the United States. They exist
outside the United States. We want to be
able to reach those folks and tell them
these stories. When I think about my
role as CEO, as we try to actually build
the future, I think about how do I get
our story in a way that is digestible
because the people who think about these
things, everyone wants to cure cancer. I
don't need a story behind curing cancer.
I just need a story about like how we're
going to get there and how curing cancer
is actually going to be one step on the
road to solving disease at large.
>> Yeah. I'm just kind of looking through
some of the summaries of the last stuff
that we talked about. These are things
that really stick out to me and then
it's like, okay, when I think of
aerospace and I am not educated. I was
not tracking it in the way that you were
or like a Steve Jervson who's been just
fascinated by this stuff since day zero.
>> Yeah.
But when I think of say
NASA and again I don't know what I'm
talking about but I think about NASA and
the government is incredibly
slowm moving and resistant to change
because there are going to be a million
different reasons. So it's like okay how
did not to
designate
Elon Musk as like the paragon of all
great things and like archangel of
capitalism but like he's done some
pretty amazing stuff right flaws and
warts aside for now
>> he's the greatest currently living
American industrialist I don't know how
anyone could possibly disagree with at
least that piece [laughter]
>> yeah with that piece so with you and
unlocking capital markets capital
formation to support this long-term
vision. There are people who have
seemingly done this kind of stuff,
meaning patient capital, long-term
capital, vast quantities of money, who
have done this before. SpaceX, I don't
think would be the only example, at
least in terms of like training Wall
Street to be like, "It's fine. Jeff is
going to figure it out. He told us what
he's going to do." Like Amazon is also
pretty fascinating example of sort of
disciplining Wall Street to be like,
"Oh, we're the only company that
analysts are going to give a pass on."
[laughter] like
not being profitable for a hundred
years.
>> Yeah.
>> And by the way, if you break even
exactly every year, like that's not an
accident. [laughter]
Pretty amazing. Financial planning. What
do you feel like you most need to do? Is
it getting on the road and delivering a
concise message to
sovereign wealth funds? In your mind,
are you like within three years, five
years, we outgrow
the vast majority of venture capital
firms and okay, maybe we step up and get
a some PE firms. I mean, you already
have some patient capital on the cap
table.
>> Yeah.
>> What do you view as the main dominoes
that you need to tip over or at least
conditions you need to set so that you
can execute on what you're describing?
Let's wheel it back to one of the other
great capitalists and industrialists of
the 20th and 21st century, Jeff Bezos,
>> because he actually did things very
differently than how Elon approached
SpaceX in terms of building a company
that is incredibly complex, incredibly
long-term minded, but he did it in the
public market. And you could argue that
Tesla has done that as well. And I think
that there's an argument to be had
there. But looking at what Amazon did,
the thing I think every entrepreneur in
the world should read is the correlated
first public year to last year of
Bezos's reign over Amazon investor
letters. There's like a a Google doc
link online that someone just put them
all into 178 page PDF. And I think
everyone should sit down and spend an
afternoon drinking coffee and reading
them, knowing what happens with Amazon,
reading 1998 through the dot bubble
burst, through the e-commerce
generation, through social media,
through everyone coming online in our
online world today. and watching how
Jeff puts forward his vision of the
future
is that it both gives you a lot of
respect of course the things he saw
coming but the thing that I respect
about it as being a public company or
going about building capital in that
sort of a way is you need to say what
you're doing in a way that makes sense
for your investors and I think for
Amazon they were incredibly undervalued
until they weren't right for a very long
time Amazon was trading at like a pretty
low PD ratio and then all of a sudden
people were like, "What is AWS by the
way?" And it was [laughter] like an
explosion.
>> It's our side hustle. Little side
hustle.
>> Well, it's like 2017 or 2018. I feel
like they went from $120 a share to over
$1,500 a share. Like in what seemed like
no amount of time is all of a sudden
people were like, "Hold on, wait. maybe
owning all levels of the infrastructure
and deployment ecosystem plus the brand
plus then building your brands on top
plus also kind of owning the internet in
a way because what is AWS by the way
it's $25 billion behemoth stuck inside
this company and they rocketed from like
I don't remember what their market cap
was before that but then you know to one
of the largest companies in the world
and that is you know like everything
that's great a overnight success 20
years in the making But if you read the
letters and you see it over time, you
see them making bets. Not every bet paid
off because not every bet should. But I
believe it's very important. I'm saying
this, Tim, because you asked, "What do I
think I need to do?" I think we need to
say what we're doing and we need to say
it publicly. We need to say it because
it will attract partners. We need to say
it because it will remind people who are
on this mission with us about what we
are building to. I think that you know
obviously if you invested in Amazon's
IPO you would have been very happy in
2014 with the performance of your
investment from then to then but then if
you invested in Amazon in 2014 you'd be
very happy with the last 12 years of
performance of that stock as well
because they continued to make those
investments but you have to have people
understanding your message and you need
to say it right you say it every day you
say like a mantra we are changing the
pace of medicine because what happens is
the exit ramp comes. If you're doing
things great, the exit ramp will always
come. You need to ask yourself if you
should get off the highway. And
understanding and reminding yourself
about what you're building every single
day helps you understand whether or not
you need to get off the highway. And I'm
not saying every single person should
keep their head down and try to build a
generational company when someone comes
out and offers you an outsized amount of
of return on your dollar. like you have
stakeholders, you have shareholders, you
have people you have promised a piece to
and you need to be a diligent steward of
their capital and be able to create
value in that way. But I do think that
it helps frame like what is our current
value that is different than our market
cap whether we're private or public.
There's a story about Amazon I think
during the.com boom I think this is
about Bezos where he wrote something
like we are not our market cap like
across like every board every chalkboard
or whiteboard in the Amazon headquarters
during the com bubble burst because
obviously the tide went out on everyone
who operated through the internet
because no one could discern the
difference between you know a zero
revenue let's get the most people on our
website company and an Amazon who is
actually building something real and so
it's very important to understand your
value in order to understand what would
be an outsized you know near-term value
if you know an acquirer comes along or
or just like how we're going to build
things because it's not about near-term
perception it's about long-term goal and
I like to think about this investment
philosophy when I look at someone like
Josh Kushner and how he's made just like
this incredible run at Thrive Capital I
think when I look at some of those great
investors who have made like these high
conviction bets. It seems like they're
able to identify this moment in time for
companies that is postconviction,
preconensus. The ones who know, we're
postconviction. We're no longer saying,
"Can we do this?" We're like, "Oh my
god, this is going to work." But it's
pre-conensus because not everyone has
caught on yet or not everyone is
convinced, right? There's a data set
that insiders and technologists or
whoever sit there and they go, "Oh my
god, I think we're there." There's a
moment, you know, if you go back and
look at OpenAI or Anthrop or any of
these companies, there's a moment
probably in the late 2010s when OpenAI
was running where folks internally
telling the story. If you listen to them
are like, "Oh my god, this is like
accelerating, right? Before we got Dali,
before we got Chat GPT, before we had
these tools, there was an internal
postconviction moment." And then of
course there's the oh wow, I think this
beats the Turing test. We're post
consensus. No one is, I think, going to
be able to debate that AI is going to
completely upend the way that everyone
lives their life going forward. And
that's the consensus moment. That's the
500 billion plus market cap moment for
all of these companies.
>> And so we need to understand where our
postconviction moment is and then we
need to build to bring folks around to
the postconensus moment. One question
popped into my head earlier that I
wanted to ensure I didn't forget which
is and I don't have a strong feeling one
way or the other but the Madna story is
so apt in so many ways and and yet
there's a fly in the ointment which is
[laughter]
broadly speaking but even more
specifically you know COVID vaccine has
become so politicized
that despite what any one individual
might think they may just need to fall
in line with kind of [laughter]
party templates or whatever you might
talk about depending on who you're
talking to and I'm wondering if that has
presented any problem
>> or if it is behind closed doors and
closed session it doesn't really matter
thinking about that analogy there's
probably better or maybe not better but
like different sorts of analogies you
could use there that are just less
politically charged because there's no
reason to wade into politically charged
waters to explain these sorts things.
Another great example could just be like
the original biotech
story, right, around like people using
technology to make insulin. We used to
use pig pancreases, harvest them, grind
them up, isolate the insulin, put it
out. And the birth of biotechnology was
around people taking the insulin gene,
putting it into bacteria and getting the
bacteria to actually make the insulin
protein and then isolating the protein
from there. But that actually became a
platform because then what did people
do? They they created herptin and other
sorts of medicines by taking other
proteins and dropping it in.
>> Growth hormone.
>> Growth hormone. Yeah. [clears throat]
>> Exactly. And that's like the basis of
like the genesis of biotechn. That's the
genent story. That is also what Genzyme
did when this sort of by coastal war
between San Francisco and Boston that's
always existed in biotechnology which I
which I absolutely love. I think it
makes things a lot more interesting and
just sort of gives a good view on the
cultures that sat 50 years before any of
us were here that I think is actually
maybe even a more powerful story and you
know we built those platforms and those
companies built incredible value and
then we got away from it then we got
more to like okay now biotechnology is a
tool let's get back to drug development
and capital markets skated you know in
the '9s when pharma companies began
verticularizing and consolidating they
began and pulling in, you know, even the
big guys themselves, you know, Bristol
Meyer, Squib, BMS, that's a big pharma
company. Why does it have that name?
Because it used to be three companies.
You talk to people who worked in, you
know, the 80s and the 90s, they're like,
well, I used to work for Bristol. I used
to work for Myers. I worked for Myers
Squib. They started pulling in. Then
once they pulled in, they realized they
were so large that they couldn't do
research anymore. So, they started
buying small companies. And so, what did
our capital markets do? They started
building for that acquisition. The
problem that becomes on a on a timeline
like that though is the whole industry
begins to skate where the capital at the
other end of the market is pulling. And
if that capital is M&A, mergers and
acquisitions, buyups from big pharma,
then everyone in the innovation industry
is focusing on what pharma wants to buy.
>> What kind of shoes pharma wants to wear?
>> Yeah. Well, what's pharma doing today?
What's the M&A situation look like
today? to the point where like this is
an actual saying in biotechnology
investing circles. It's called short the
launch. It means that when a biotech
company like mine has gotten a drug
approved and is going to launch it
themselves, like actually take it
commercial themselves, investors in the
public market on on the whole will short
that because they think a biotech
company will mess it up because there's
like the muscle doesn't exist anymore
because so few companies do it that
they're like short it. No, they're gonna
mess it up. They're gonna miss their
projection and and their stock's gonna
dip and we're gonna win. And that's just
the market reacting to reality. It's not
nefarious necessarily, but that sort of
gives you a picture of how biotechnology
has basically succumbed itself to be a
little brother to the pharmaceutical
industry, a a pool of drugs that they
can buy, which that's wonderful. like
like Google buying your startup in the
tech industry is a great exit for
everyone involved. However, if the
entire tech industry was reliant on
Meta, Google, Netflix, whoever buying
your company, then you would see a lot
weirder and less ambitious dynamics at
the entrepreneurial side because you'd
just be trying to figure out what is
Sundar going to do a year from now. You
can't build for a select group of
people's tastes and that's the risk I
think biotechnology has found itself in.
Yeah. Are there any more recent
examples? They don't have to be biotech,
but outside of SpaceX, outside of
Amazon, not going as far back as Jenzyme
and Janentech, although it is fun to
look back at that, particularly
when you read some of these books on the
birth of say Janentech and you realize
it's like, yeah, it's top of mind, so
I'll mention it. But it was kind of like
Apple, right? you had this like rag tag
group of renegades in a garage really
flying by the seat of their pants and
doing some wild [__] right? And as you
said, decades later
when everyone is contorting themselves
into their probably inaccurate
prediction of what the, you know, heads
of corp dev or the CEO of big companies
1, two, and three are thinking. the
dynamic is just completely different.
The incentives are are very different.
The timelines are very different. How
you think about building on success, I
mean to get back to like the platform,
right? It's like if every drug has to
individually go from A to Z, you don't
have a platform. It's like if you're
kind of skipping A to M and you're
starting at M, okay, maybe you have a
platform. I'm wondering if there are any
other entrepreneurs or companies that
stand out to you as
having parallels to what you're trying
to do. Before I get to that, just
because you just compared Janentech and
Apple and I want to point something out
too. I don't know if you know this. I
don't know if anyone knows this. So Art
Levenson, who was the CEO of Janentech
from 1995 to 200 something, was also on
the Apple board of directors and became
the chairman replacing Steve Jobs in
2011 or something.
>> I did not know that. There's a wonderful
story about the read through and Art
Levenston and his partnership and and
friendship with Steve Jobs between the
two of them. They are highly highly
related companies and I think that is
actually why I spend time studying
technology and why you see a increased
interest especially in the last 5 to 10
years among you know traditional tech
and deep tech Silicon Valley investors
like Andre Horowitz or Playground Global
one of my investors like moving into
biotechnology seeing a resurgence of
this both technological and and cultural
outlook towards building big ideas
around what we can do with technology
applied to biology and human health
>> and that I think is really exciting.
There's all sorts of examples of
companies that have built things like
this. I think that Tesla's a great
example. Well, maybe we should move away
from an Elon [clears throat]
analogy. I don't mean to like ride on
Elon. I just I have spent a lot of time
like studying him, but like Apple is a
great example of a company that sort of
built like a core platform that solved a
delivery problem.
>> Mhm. [clears throat] not looking at the
early Steve Jobs first tenure at the
company but when he when he re came back
to the company
>> I don't remember what year that was 98
maybe or something he came back to the
company cut like 80% of their product
offerings refined it and then created
the smartphone era upended blackberry in
a way that was like so I mean they were
they were hated on yeah
>> but he created the del that's a delivery
system that's what a smartphone is Apple
and the phone and the iPad, they're
delivery systems of all of the
technology workplace that can work
within them. And by by creating that
delivery system, your iPhone and you are
going to work within our ecosystem and
attacking that market by, you know,
partnering with with Jon IV and creating
a culture around it, but also creating
an ease of operability. You created an
an ability for other companies to
deliver their products to consumers. So
many companies don't build smartphones,
but they build on smartphones, right?
That's a that's a delivery platform that
also is constantly getting better. The
iPhone 1, I actually just saw an iPhone
1 recently at a friend's house. He like
still has his original iPhone one. I was
like, "God, your dad must have been
rich."
>> No copy paste.
>> Yeah, no copy [laughter] paste. Like
this thick, man. It's this thick. It's
this thick, but it's also the screen is
so I thought it was so big. It's so
small. Each successive one increased its
capabilities, increased its form factor,
increased what it could do, became a
better delivery system, eventually
supplanted, right? Over time, you
stopped using the earlier versions, but
each one, of course, had a ton of value.
And Apple delivered things to you. They
had the iTunes store, they sold you
music, they used it to deliver their own
products. They were also a platform for
other people to deliver their products.
And that created one of the most
valuable companies in the entire world.
And you think about what creates the
most value and what changes the way that
we interact with the world around us. It
is delivery solutions. It is being able
to launch enough satellites to put
internet anywhere in the world and do
that on an economical basis. It is a
place where you could design any sort of
software and get it into the hands of
almost every single person on this
planet or at least every single person
in the developed world. And I think for
medicine it is being able to reach any
cell in the body and get the exact type
of protein that we want there. And in
the near term it'll be more traditional
medicines. It'll be we need to design
them and then we need to create them and
then we need to test them and we need to
get them to patients and you need to
develop for larger patient populations.
But if you want to see what that sort of
technology enables on a 10 to 20 year
timeline, it's personalization. Because
once you have a good view or a great
understanding of how these delivery
solutions work and you have the
infrastructure, manufacturing, clinical
deployment, getting to patients both
across the country, across the world,
then you can start to be like, well, why
aren't we just building bespoke
therapies? Right now, the economics
don't work. But the economics of Spotify
didn't work in 2001.
>> Yeah.
>> If Spotify's entire market was through
your desktop computer, you could have
never built Spotify. But you can when
they're smartphones. You can when people
always have it in their car. And so in
2011, that's a much better time for
Spotify to exist as a company and really
take off. Now, that is, I think, where
the future of medicine sort of goes
towards a hyperpersonalization.
We're starting to see people trying to
build personalized medicine right now.
There's a story baby KJ that came out
last year in the New York Times.
Jennifer Dana was involved. A number of
hospitals, they corrected a baby. But
the reality of that baby's genetic
problem was that the the change needed
to be made in the liver.
>> Mhm.
>> And that's great for that baby. And
there's other diseases that we could do
that for in the liver.
>> In the liver. Yeah.
>> But we're going to run out. Kidney
disease is not going to be solved in the
liver. nerve degeneration is not going
to be solved in the liver. And so we
have to find the other solutions and
then build infrastructure that creates
an economically viable path forward to
where bespoke medicines are possible.
>> Yeah, we'll put in a link to baby KJ.
>> Sorry, I just threw in
>> No, it was great. Which I hadn't
actually read when it came out.
>> Threw in a whole new idea. My larger
piece of where I think the future of
medicine is going.
>> Yeah. which I guess we're not going to
get into today, but you you and I have
texted on like why has Crisper not
delivered on the expectations that had
everybody euphoric X years in the past,
but in this particular case, yeah, KJ
became the first patient to receive a
personalized systemic crisperbase
editing therapy, saving him from a fatal
liver condition. So, people can read
more about that. Well, this is super
fun. Nice to see you, man.
>> Good to see you. and happy to try to be
helpful anytime you know how to find me.
I'm easy.
>> All right, man.